Guide to the Richard Pollay. Tobacco industry promotion (TIPS) collection, 1885-2012 and undated RL.11612
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- 2013 Addition, 1922-2012; undated; 14
  - Research and Writing by Others, 1933-2012; undated; 195
    - Gerard Hastings and Kathryn Angus--When is social marketing not social marketing?, 2011 (Box A9)
    - Gerard Hastings and Lynn MacFadyen--Keep Smiling No One's Going to Die: An analysis of internal documents from the tobacco industry's main UK advertising agencies, 2000 (Box A9)
    - Gregory Connolly et al--Public Attitudes Regarding Banning of Cigarettes and Regulation of Nicotine, 2012 (Box A9)
    - Health Behavior News--Tobacco Companies Find Loopholes in Settlement Stance on Outdoor Ads, 2008 (Box A9)
    - Henry Farrell--The Billion Dollar Smoke: A Working Truth in Reference to Cigarettes and Cigarette Smoking, 1933 (Box A9)
    - Henry Saffer and Frank Chaloupka--Tobacco Advertising: Economic Theory and International Evidence, working paper 6958, 1999 (Box A9)
    - Janet Hoek and Sandra Jones--Regulation, public health and social marketing: a behaviour change trinity, 2011 (Box A9)
    - Janine Paynter and Richard Edwards--The impact of tobacco promotion at the point of sale: A systematic review, 2009 (Box A9)
    - Jennifer Ibrahim and Stanton Glantz--The Rise and Fall of Tobacco Control Media Campaigns, 1967-2006, 2007 (Box A9)
    - Jennifer Kreslake et at--Tobacco Industry Control of Menthol in Cigarettes and Targeting of Adolescents and Young Adults, 2008 (Box A9)
    - Joanna Cohen et al--Tobacco Promotions at Point-of-Sale: The Last Hurrah, 2008 (Box A9)
    - John Ayanian and Paul Cleary--Perceived Risks of Heart Disease and Cancer Among Cigarette Smokers, 1999 (Box A9)
    - John Solow--Exorcising the Ghost of Cigarette Advertising Past: Collusion, Regulation and Fear Advertising, 2001 (Box A9)
      Includes copy of 1955 FTC news release announcing cigarette advertising regulations, and Advertising Age articles on medical claims in cigarette ads
    - Jon Wiener--Big Tobacco and the Historians, 2010 (Box A9)
    - Juliana Doxey and David Hammond--Deadly in pink: the impact of cigarette packaging among young women (Box A9)
    - K.L. Lum et al--Signed, sealed and delivered: "big tobacco" in Hollywood 1927-1951, 2008 (Box A9)
    - Kim Klausner--Menthol cigarettes and smoking initiation: a tobacco industry perspective, 2011 (Box A9)
    - Kurt Ribisl--Research Gaps Related to Tobacco Product Marketing and Sales in the Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act, 2011 (Box A9)
    - Lisa Henriksen--Comprehensive tobacco marketing restrictions: promotion, packaging, price and place, 2012 (Box A9)
    - Lisa Henriksen et al--Targeted Advertising, Promotion, and Price For Menthol Cigarettes in California High School Neighborhoods, 2011 (Box A9)
    - Louis Kyriakoudes--Affidavit filed for Gadaleta v. AC&S, Inc. et al, 2004 (Box A9)
    - M. Wakefield et al--The cigarette pack as image: new evidence from tobacco industry documents, 2002 (Box A9)
    - Marc Weinberger et al--Joe Camel: Post-mortem of a brand spokesperson, 2010 (Box A9)
    - Mariaelena Gonzalez et al--Through tobacco industry eyes: civil society and the FCTC process from Philip Morris and British American Tobacco's perspectives, 2011 (Box A9)
    - Mark Reed et al--The temporal relationship between advertising and sales of low-tar cigarettes, 2006 (Box A9)
    - Martin Foster et al--The state of knowledge regarding tobacco harm, 1920-1964: industry and public health service perspectives, 2006 (Box A9)
    - Marvin Goldberg--Expert report (prototype), undated (Box A9)
    - Marvin Goldberg--How the tobacco industry continues to dupe the public into believing light cigarettes provide lower health risks than regular cigarettes (Senate testimony), 2007 (Box A9)
    - Marvin Goldberg--Why New Tobacco "Harm Reduction" Products Should Be Regulated, 2008 (Box A9)
    - Marvin Goldberg et al--The role of tobacco advertising and promotion: themes employed in litigation by tobacco industry witnesses, 2006 (Box A9)
    - Melanie Wakefield--Welcome to cardboard country: how plain packaging could change the subjective experience of smoking, 2011 (Box A9)
    - Nathaniel Wander et al--Corporate hegemony and social permission in Virginia Slims' "peculiar marriage" of tennis and tobacco, 2008 (Box A10)
    - National Cancer Institute--Monograph 19: The Role of the Media in Promoting and Reducing Tobacco Use, Executive Summary, 2008 (Box A10)
    - Norbert Hirschhorn and Stan Shatenstein, curators--The Best of the Lighter Side (tobacco related comics) 1992-2009, 2012 (Box A10)
    - O.B.J. Carter et al--The effect of retail cigarette pack displays on unplanned purchases: results from immediate postpurchase interviews, 2009 (Box A10)
    - Patricia McDaniel and Ruth Malone--"I always thought they were all pure tobacco": American smokers' perceptions of "natural" cigarettes and tobacco industry advertising strategies, 2007 (Box A10)
    - Peter Morris--"Personally, I Have Nothing Against Smoking": The Lethal Alliance between Baseball and the Cigarette, 2009 (Box A10)
    - Philip Morris--Editorial that ran in Black Enterprise voicing support for black consumers, 1988 (Box A10)
    - Philip Smith et al--Correcting Over 50 Years of Tobacco Industry Misinformation, 2011 (Box A10)
    - Phyra McCandless et al--Quid Pro Quo: Tobacco Companies and the Black Press, 2012 (Box A10)
    - R.M. Davis--British-American Tobacco ghost-wrote reports on tobacco advertising bans by the International Advertising Association and J.J. Boddewyn, 2008 (Box A10)
    - Reiner Hanewinkel et al--Cigarette Advertising and Adolescent Smoking, 2010 (Box A10)
    - Reiner Hanewinkel et al--Cigarette Advertising and Teen Smoking Initiation, 2011 (Box A10)
    - Richard Daynard and Eric LeGresley--Product Liability, 2012 (Box A10)
    - Robert Jackler and Hussein Samji--The Price Paid: Manipulation of Otolaryngologists by the Tobacco Industry to Obfuscate the Emerging Truth that Smoking Causes Cancer, 2011 (Box A10)
    - Robert John et al--Point-of-Sale Marketing of Tobacco Products: Taking Advantage of the Socially Disadvantaged, 2009 (Box A10)
    - Robert Proctor--Golden Holocaust (Excerpt), 2011 (Box A10)
    - Robert Proctor--History of the discovery of the cigarette-lung cancer link: evidentiary traditions, corporate deinal, global toll, 2012 (Box A10)
    - Robert Proctor--Tobacco and Health (expert witness report from USA v. Philip Morris et al), 2004 (Box A10)
    - Ron Borland et al--Impact of Graphic and Text Warnings on Cigarette Packs: Findings from Four Countries over Five Years, 2009 (Box A10)
    - Ron Borland et al--Impact of structural packaging design on young adult smokers' perceptions of tobacco products, 2011 (Box A10)
    - Sarah Lochlann Jain--"Come Up to the Kool Taste": African American Upward Mobility and the Semiotics of Smoking Menthols, 2003 (Box A10)
    - Seema Mutti et al--Beyond light and mild: cigarette brand descriptors and perceptions of risk in the International Tobacco Control (ITC) Four Country Survey, 2011 (Box A10)
    - Semira Gonseth et al--The tobacco industry's past role in weight control related to smoking, 2011 (Box A10)
    - Sherry Emery et al--The Effects of Smoking-Related Television Advertising on Smoking and Intentions to Quit Among Adults in the United States 1999-2007, 2012 (Box A10)
    - Simon Chapman and Gemma Derrick--Bibliograhic analysis of papers and authors published in Tobacco Control 1998-September 2011, 2012 (Box A10)
    - Stacey Anderson--Marketing of menthol cigarettes and consumer perceptions: a review of tobacco industry documents, 2011 (Box A10)
    - Stacey Anderson et al--Implications of the federal court order banning the terms "light" and "mild": what difference could it make?, 2007 (Box A10)
    - Stacey Anderson et al--Tobacco documents research methodology, 2011 (Box A10)
    - Stanton Glantz--Pinocchio shows how to end the tobacco epidemic, 2012 (Box A10)
    - Stella Aguinaga Bialous and Silvy Peeters--A brief overview of the tobacco industry in the last 20 years, 2012 (Box A10)
    - Surgeon General--Preventing Tobacco Use Among Youth and Young Adults, 2012 (Box A10)
    - Suzan Burton et al--The association between seeing retail displays of tobacco and tobacco smoking and purchase: findings from a diary style survey, 2011 (Box A10)
    - Terrell Stevenson and Robert Proctor--The Secret and Soul of Marlboro: Philip Morris and the Origins, Spread, and Denial of Nicotine Freebasing, 2008 (Box A10)
    - Tess Boley Cruz et al--The Menthol Marketing Mix: Targeted Promotions for Focus Communities in the United States, 2010 (Box A10)
    - Timothy Dewhirst--New directions in tobacco promotion and brand communication, 2009 (Box A10)
    - Timothy Dewhirst--Tobacco Portrayals in U.S. Advertising and Entertainment Media, 2008 (Box A10)
    - Timothy Dewhirst and Robert Sparks--Brand mismanagement: Rothmans cigarette marketing 1957-2000, 2011 (Box A10)
    - Timothy Dewhirst and Wonkyong Lee--Cigarette advertising in the Republic of Korea: A case illustration of The One, undated (Box A10)
    - Tobacco Control Legal Consortium--Regulating Tobacco Marketing: A "Commercial Speech" Factsheet for State and Local Governments, 2010 (Box A10)
    - Tom McNichol--Mint that Kills: The Curious Life of Menthol Cigarettes, 2011 (Box A10)
    - Wilm Quentin et al--Advertising bans as a means of tobacco control policy: a systematic literature review of time-series analyses, 2007 (Box A10)
    - Youn Ok Lee and Stanton Glantz--Menthol: putting the pieces together, 2011 (Box A10)
    - Yussuf Saloojee and Ross Hammond--Fatal Deception: The tobacco industry's "new" global standards for tobacco marketing, 2001 (Box A10)
  - 1019. Tobacco Promotion in Circus Programs, 1923-1999; undated; 196
    - Circus banner photographs, undated (Box A10)
    - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1995-1999 (Box A10)
    - Hagenbeck-Wallace Circus--Magazine and Daily Review, 1933 (Box A10)
    - Ringling Brothers and Barnum & Bailey--Magazine and Daily Review, 1923 (Box A10)
    - Ringling Brothers and Barnum & Bailey--Magazine and Daily Review, 1935-1957; 6 folders (Box A11)
    - Ringling Brothers and Barnum & Bailey--Souvenir Program, 1958-1966 (Box A11)
- 2020 Addition, 1936; 1 Files
  - American Tobacco, Lucky Strike "A Light Smoke" poster, 1936 (Oversize-folder 1)